<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2022 Thomas Perl <m@thp.io> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.sourceforge.wavbreaker</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <content_rating>none</content_rating>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>wavbreaker</name>
  <summary>GUI tool to split WAV, MP2 and MP3 files</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
    wavbreaker's purpose in life is to take a WAV file and break it up
    into multiple WAV files. It makes a clean break at the correct position
    to burn the files to an Audio CD without any dead air between the tracks.
    </p>

    <p>
    wavbreaker also supports breaking up MP2 and MP3 files without re-encoding
    meaning it's fast and there is no generational loss. Decoding (using mpg123)
    is only done for playback and waveform display.
    </p>

    <p>
    The GUI displays a waveform summary of the entire file at the top. The middle
    portion displays a zoomed-in view that allows you to select where to start
    playing and where it will make the break. The bottom portion contains a list
    of track breaks. You may change file names and uncheck parts that you do not
    want to have written out to disk when saving.
    </p>

    <p>
    There is also a command line tool wavmerge to merge WAV files together.
    If you download a show and don't like how it was tracked, you can merge them
    together with wavmerge and then break them back up with wavbreaker. The
    wavmerge tool will only work on files that have the same format (for example,
    44.100 Hz sample rate, 16-bit sample size, etc.).
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.sourceforge.wavbreaker.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Splitting an audio file into multiple parts</caption>
      <image>https://github.com/thp/wavbreaker/raw/master/data/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://wavbreaker.sourceforge.io/</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>wavbreaker</binary>
    <binary>wavcli</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.16" date="2022-12-20">
      <description>
        <p>Support for reading Ogg Vorbis files (writing not yet implemented)</p>
        <p>New "wavcli" command-line tool exposing wavbreaker's features to CLI users</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15" date="2022-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Support for lossless cutting of MPEG-1 Audio Layer II (MP2) files</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.14" date="2022-03-17">
      <description>
        <p>Continous integration migrated from Travis to Github,
          plus various small patches from distributions merged.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
